Guide to the New York University Archives Collection of Faculty Publications, 1844-1994 RG.1.1
New York University Archives
- Faculty Publications
  - Draper, John William; Scientific Memoirs, Being Experimental Contributions to a Knowledge of Radiant Energy, 1878 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Fryer, Douglas; The Measurement of Interests, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Gillett, E.H.; The Moral System, with an Historical and Critical Introduction, 1874 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Proceedings of the Meeting of the Officers of the Colleges and Academies, with address by Taylor Lewis on Liberal Education, 1863 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Palmer, Richard, and Otto, Christian F.; Weissenhoff 1927 and the Modern Movement in Architecture, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Park, Joseph Hendershot; British Prime Ministers of the Nineteenth Century: Policies and Speeches (2 copies), 1950 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Pollock, Thomas Clark; The Nature of Literature: Its Relation to Science, Religion, and Human Experience, 1942 (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Pike, James S.; The Prostrate State: South Carolina Under Negro Government, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Knowlton, Daniel C., and Tilton, J. Warren; Motion Pictures in History Teaching, 1929 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Brill, Jeanette G., and Payne, E. George; The Adolescent Court and Crime Prevention, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Prokosch, E.; The Sounds and History of the German Language, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Paine, Martyn; A Discourse on the Soul and Instinct, 1849 (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - Labberton and Marks; The Marine Engineer's Handbook, 1945 (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble; The Family on Gramercy Park (2 copies), 1949 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227014 3
  - Radossawljewitsch, Paul R.; Das Fortschreiten des Vergessens mit der Zeit, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Magee, James Dysart; Materials for the Study of Banking, 1923 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - MacCracken, John Henry; College and Commonwealth, 1920 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; The Three Essentials (2 copies), 1901 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; Andrew Haswell Green: A Memorial Address, 1903 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Henry Mitchell MacCracken: In Memoriam (2 copies), 1923 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Magoffin, R.V.D. and Davis, Emily C.; Magic Spades: The Romance of Archaeology, 1929 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Kimball, Fiske; American Architecture, 1928 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Granniss, Ruth Shepard; The Work of a Book Club, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous publications in chemistry by Arthur E. Hill, 1923-1931 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Richards, Theodore W., ed.; The Scientific Work of Morris Loeb, 1913 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; The Hall of Fame, 1901 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Magoffin, Ralph VanDeman; The Lure and Lore of Archaeology, 1930 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - MacDougall, Robert; The General Problems of Psychology Conceptions, 1922 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Reed, Anna Y.; Occupational Placement, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; Lives of the Leaders of Our Church Universal (3 vols.), 1879 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Hill, A.E.; Miscellaneous Publications in Chemistry, 1904-1922 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Loomis, Elias; The Recent Progress of Astronomy, 1856 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Bessinger, Jess B. and Raymo, Robert R., eds.; Medieval Studies in Honor of Lillian Herlands Hornstein, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - The Tercentenary Announcements, 1609-1909: New York University Bulletin (2 copies) (Box 15, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227015 0
  - Shaw, Charles Gray; The Road to Culture, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - MacCracken, Henry Mitchell; Urgent Eastern Questions, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Stanton, Frank; Mass Media and Culture, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Turner, John Roscoe; The Ricardian Rent Theory in Early American Economics, 1921 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Millican, Charles Bowie; The First English Translation of the Prophecies of Merlin, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Bond, R.P., Millican, C.B., Bowyer, J.W., and Smith, G.H.; A Collection of Chaucer Allusions, 1931 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Ray, Gordon N.; Nineteenth Century English Fiction, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Sihler, E.G.; Three American Essays, 1902-1905 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - MacCracken, Henry Noble; The Family on Gramercy Park, 1949 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Shaw, Charles Gray; The Ground and Goal of Human Life, 1919 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Loomis, Elias; Treatise on Astronomy, 1865 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Wilkes, John W.; A Whig in Power, 1964 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Peel, Roy V.; The Political Clubs of New York City, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Sihler, E.G.; The Annals of Caesar, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Sihler, E.G.; Testimonium Animae, 1908 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Shaw, Charles Gray; The Value and Dignity of Human Life, 1911 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Shaw, Charles Gray; The Road to Happiness, 1937 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Hering, D.W.; Art in Clockmaking and Watchmaking, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Larkin, Oliver W.; Samuel F.B. Morse: An American Democratic Art, 1954 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Mitchell, Allan C.G. and Zemansky, Mark W.; Resonance Radiation and Excited Atoms, 1934 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Sihler, E.G.; Cicero of Arpinum, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Shaw, Charles Gray; The Ego and Its Place in the World, 1913 (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - Morse, Edward Lind, ed.; Samuel F.B. Morse: His Letters and Journals, 1914 (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Vennard, John K.; Elementary Fluid Mechanics, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227016 8
  - Warren, Edward H.; Excerpts from Spartan Education, 1943 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Trager, Frank N., ed.; Behavior Science Bibliographies: Annotated Bibliography of Burma, 1956 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    bar code#: 3 1142 04227016 8
  - Smith, David Nichol, and McAdam, Edward L., eds.; The Poems of Samuel Johnson, 1941 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - McDonald, Philip B.; A Saga of the Seas, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Rollins, Hyder E.; A Gorgeous Gallery of Gallant Inventions, 1926 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Rusk, Howard A.; A World to Care For, 1972 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - The Collected Works of Martin Andre Rosanoff, undated (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Rollins, Hyder Edward; The Pack of Autolycus, 1927 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Prentiss, G.L.; The Union Theological Seminary in the City of New York, 1899 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Saville, Thorndyke; New Horizons in Engineering Education, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Rosenblatt, Louise; Literature as Explanation, 1938 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - The Tercentenary Announcements, 1609-1909: New York University Bulletin (3 copies) (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Mergers and the Law, 1929 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Watkins, Myron W.; Oil: Stabilization or Conservation?, 1937 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Walsh, William F.; Outlines of the History of English and American Law, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Roe, Joseph Wickham; English and American Toolbuilders, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Gishford, Anthony, ed.; Tempo Quarterly (2 copies), 1951-1952 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Shotwell, James T., ed.; Government of Continental Europe, 1940 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Stahl, W.H.; The Systematic Handbook in Antiquity and the Early Middle Ages, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Stahl, William H.; "To A Better Understanding of Martianus Capella" (from Speculum), 1965 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - Stahl, William H.; Ptolemese Geography, 1953 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Millican, Charles Bowie; Spenser and the Arthurian Legend, 1930 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Max, Louis William; The Time Relations of the Electrical and Mechanical Response of Heart Muscle, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227017 6
  - Stahl, William Harris; The Greek Heliocentric Theory and Its Abandonment, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Sihler, E.G.; From Augustus to Augustine (2 copies), 1923 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Sihler, Ernest G.; From Maumee to Thames and Tiber, 1930 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - McAdam, E.L.; "Dr. Johnson and Saunders Welch's Proposals" (from Review of English Studies), 1953 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - McAdam, E.L.; Dr. Johnson and the English Law, 1951 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - McAdam, E.L.; Samuel Johnson: Diaries, Prayers, and Annals, 1958 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - McAdam, E.L., and Milne, George; Johnson's Dictionary, 1963 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Federal Energy Administration: Project Independence, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Federal Energy Administration: Project Independence Report, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - McAdam, E.L.; "Wordsworth's Shipwreck" (from the PMLA), 1962 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - McAdam, E.L., ed.; The Yale Edition of the Works of Samuel Johnson, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - McConnell, John W.; The Evolution of Social Classes, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - McConnell, John W.; The Basic Teachings of the Great Economists, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - McAdam, E.L., and Milne, George, eds.; A Johnson Reader, 1964 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Rollins, Hyder E.; Cavalier and Puritan, 1923 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Rollins, Hyder E., ed.; Index to the Ballad Entries in the Stationers' Registers, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Rollins, Hyder E., ed.; A Handful of Pleasant Delights, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Park, Jacqueline; Charlie's Back in Town, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227858 3
  - Watkins, Myron W.; Industrial Combinations and Public Policy, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Nason, Arthur Huntington; Short Themes, 1909 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Zurcher, Arnold John; The Experiment with Democracy in Central Europe, 1933 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Watt, Homer Andrew; Bulletin of the University of Wisconsin, 1910 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - The Journal of English and Germanic Philology, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Wilkens, Frederick H.; The Source of Kleist's Review: Uber den Zustand der Schwartzen in Amerika, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Wood, Wallace; Catalog of Engravings, Etchings, and Aquatints, undated (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - McMahon, A. Philip; Preface to An American Philosophy of Art, 1945 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Draper, John W.; William Lyndon Wright: A Memoir (4 copies), 1923 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Wood, Wallace, ed.; The Hundred Greatest Men (books 3 and 4), 1885 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Mallery, Richard, ed.; Master Works of Travel and Exploration, 1948 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Wolfe, Don M.; Leveller Manifestoes of the Puritan Revolution, 1944 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Rollins, Hyder E.; A Pepysian Garland, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Wendel, Hugo C.; The Evolution of Industrial Freedom in Prussia, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Lounsbury, Ralph Greenlee; The British Fishery at Newfoundland, 1634-1763, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Rollins, Hyder E., ed.; Old English Ballads, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Mallery, Richard D.; Our American Language, 1947 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Sihler, E.G.; A Lexicon to Caesar's Gallic War, 1891 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Rollins, Hyder E.; various articles, 1919-1923 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Watkins, Myron W.; various articles, 1928-1934 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Watkins, Myron W.; Business and the Law, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Watkins, Myron W.; Present Position and Prospects of Antitrust Policy, 1942 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Dworkin, Ronald, Miller, Karl, and Sennett, Richard, eds.; Humanities in Review, 1982 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227859 1
  - M'Ilvaine, Charles P.; The Evidences of Christianity, 1832 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Schlauch, Margaret, trans.; The Saga of the Volsungs, 1930 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Roelofs, H. Mark; The Language of Modern Politics, 1967 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Howe, M.A. deWolfe; James Ford Rhodes: American Historian, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Reid, James D.; The Telegraph in America, 1879 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Mason, Gregory; South of Yesterday, 1940 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Schlauch, Margaret; Chaucer's Constance and Accused Queens, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Melamid, Alexander; various articles, 1956-1959 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - various articles on English literature by Janet Spens and C. Bowie Millican, 1934-1938 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Schwartz, Bernard; Law and the Executive in Britain, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Schwarz, H. Stanley; Alexandre Dumas, fils: Dramatist, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Scott, Jonathan F.; War and Public Opinion, 1936 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Reither, Joseph, ed.; Master Works of History, 1948 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Rosenkampff, Arthur H.; Bookkeeping: Theory and Practice, 1924 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Davis, Pearce, and Meyer, Henry J., eds.; Labor Dispute Settlements in the Telephone Industry, 1942-1945, 1946 (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Meyer, Adolf E.; The Development of Education in the Twentieth Century, 1949 (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Zurcher, Arnold J.; Constitutions and Constitutional Trends Since World War II, 1951 (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Sawhill, John C., Oshima, Keichi, and Maull, Hanns, W.; Energy: Managing the Transition, 1978 (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Nuclear Power: Issues and Choices, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Nason, Arthur Huntington; Efficient Composition, 1917 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    bar code #: 3 1142 04227860 9
  - Ford Foundation; Energy: The Next 20 Years, 1979 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Smith, Edward Conrad; The Borderland in the Civil War, 1927 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Smith, D. Nichol, and McAdam, E.L.; The Poems of Samuel Johnson, 1941 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Meyer, Adolf; Voltaire: Man of Justice, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Smith, Edward Conrad, and Zurcher, Arnold John, eds.; A Dictionary of American Politics, 1944 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Nason, John Huntington; James Shirley, Dramatist, 1915 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Sprague, Charles E.; Handbook of the Volapuk, 1888 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Horne, Herman Harrell, ed.; Quintilian on Education, undated (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Stahl, William H.; By Their Maps You Shall Know Them (from Archaeology), 1955 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Stahl, William Harris; "The Ancient Greek Astronomers" (from the Classical Journal), 1951 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Stack, Herbert J., Siebrecht, Elmer B., Elkow, J. Duke, eds.; Education for Safe Living, 1949 (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Stein, Bruno; On Relief: The Economics of Poverty and Public Welfare, 1971 (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Stahl, William; Macrobias: Commentary on the Dream of Scipio, 1952 (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - South, Helen Pennock; The Proverbs of Alfred, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Smith, Homer W.; From Fish to Philosopher, 1953 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Smith, Edward Conrad; A Dictionary of American Politics, 1924 (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Sinding, Paul C.; History of Scandinavia, 1858 (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Newsom, Carroll V.; A University President Speaks Out: On Current Education, 1961 (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Nock, Francis J.; An Introduction to Scientific German, 1937 (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Taylor, W. C., A Manual of Ancient and Modern History, 1869 (Box 21, Item 1)
  - Wood, Wallace, The Hundred Greatest Men, 1892 (Box 21, Item 2)
  - Tappan, Henry P., The Elements of Logic, 1855 (Box 21, Item 3)
  - Tappan, Henry P., The Doctrine of the Will, 1840 (Box 21, Item 4)
  - Tappan, Henry P., Doctrine of the Will: Applied to Moral Agency and Responsibility, 1841 (Box 21, Item 5)
  - Loomis, Elias, Elements of Natural Philosophy, 1860 (Box 21, Item 6)
  - Loomis, Elias, The Elements of Astronomy, 1871 (Box 21, Item 7)
  - Loomis, Elias, Elements of Geometry, 1847 (Box 21, Item 8)
  - Loomis, Elias, Tables of Logarithms of Numbers, 1883 (Box 21, Item 9)
  - Lewis, Tayler, The Divine Human in the Scriptures, 1860 (Box 22, Item 1)
  - Hall, John, Eight Unto My Path, 1895 (Box 22, Item 2)
  - Loomis, Elias, A Treatise on Astronomy, 1892 (Box 22, Item 3)
  - Paine, Martin, Letters on the Cholera Asphyxia, 1832 (Box 22, Item 4)
  - Torrey, John, Compendium of the Flora of the Northern and Middle States, 1826 (Box 22, Item 5)
  - Loomis, Elias, The Elements of Arithmetic, 1863 (Box 22, Item 6)
  - Da Ponte, Lorenzo L. The Age and Rule of the Medici, 1833 (Box 22, Item 7)
  - Taylor, John S., A Review of Edwards' "Inquiry into the Freedom of Will", 1839 (Box 22, Item 8)
  - Loomis, Elias, The Elements of Algebra, 1874 (Box 22, Item 9)
  - Fuhrmann, Otto and Fritz Peters, "An Excerpt from Goethe's Faust", 1931 (Box 22, Item 10)
  - Patton, Robert P., "A Lecture on Classical and National Education", 1826 (Box 22, Item 11)
  - MacDougall, Robert, "University Training and the Doctoral Degree," reprinted from Education, 1904 (Box 22, Item 12)
  - Thiersch, Friedrich, Greek Tables on a Method of Teaching the Greek Paradigm, 1822 (Box 22, Item 13)
  - Mitchell-Vigneron, Jeannette, "Alexandre Liautard", 1982 (Box 22, Item 14)
  - Parker, Richard Alexander, "Claude de L'Estoille, Poet and Dramatist", 1930 (Box 22, Item 15)
  - Prince, J. Dyneley, "Some Passamaquoddy Witch Tales" and "On the Writing on the Wall at Belshazzar's Feast", 1868 (Box 22, Item 16)
  - Hackley, Charles W., A Treatise on Algebra, 1860 (Box 22, Item 17)
  - Loomis, Elias, Elements of Analytical Geometry and of the Differential and Integral Calculus, 1851 (Box 22, Item 18)
  - MacLay, An Address Delivered at a Public Meeting Held in Hope Street Baptist Church, Glasgow, 1840 (Box 22, Item 19)
  - Draper, John William, The Organization of Plants, 1844 (Box 23, Item 1)
  - Cousin, Victor, Elements of Psychology, 1856 (Box 23, Item 2)
  - Ellinwood, Mary G., Frank Field Ellinwood: His Life and Work, 1911 (Box 23, Item 3)
  - Guizot, M., General History of Civilization in Europe, 1846 (Box 23, Item 4)
  - Doyle, Martin (pseudonym of William Hickey), The Flower Garden, 1835 (Box 23, Item 5)
  - Henry, Caleb Sprague, A Household Liturgy, 1873 (Box 23, Item 6)
  - "Nothing to Wear: An Episode of City Life", 1857 (Box 23, Item 7)
  - Henry, C. S., Moral and Philosophical Essays, 1839 (Box 23, Item 8)
  - Lamb, Arthur B., "The Potential of Iron Calculated from Equilibria Measurements" and "An Equilibrium in the Cobaltammines", 1910-1911 (Box 23, Item 9)
  - Gerstenberg, Charles W., "Problems in Private Finance", 1916 (Box 23, Item 10)
  - Arnold, Rev. Thomas Kerchever, Cornelius Nepos, 1850 (Box 23)
  - Ermystead Grammar School, Skipton, 1877 (Box 23)
  - Noveck, Beth Simone, Smart Citizens, Smarter State, 2015 (Box 23)
  - Lempriere, J., Bilbiotheca Classica, 1832 (Box 24, Item 1)
  - Jordan, William George, Charles Waldo Haskins, 1923 (Box 24, Item 2)
  - Eddy, A. D., The Duties, Dangers, and Securities of Youth, 1836 (Box 24, Item 3)
  - Torrey, John, Natural History of New York: Botany (volume I), 1843 (Box 24, Item 4)
  - Torrey, John, Natural History of New York: Botany (volume II), 1843 (Box 24, Item 5)
  - Draper, John W., A Treatise on the Forces Which Produce the Organization of Plants, 1844 (Box 24, Item 6)
  - Edmonson, Thomas William, "Documents Extracted from the Public Record Office Concerning Skipton-in-Craven, Yorkshire", undated (Box 24, Item 7)
  - Wertenbaker, Thomas Jefferson, The Old South: The Founding of American Civilization, 1942 (Box 25, Item 1)
  - Morse, Samuel F.B., Foreign Conspiracy Against the Liberties of the United States, 1855 (Box 25, Item 2)
  - Vail, Alfred, The American Electro Magnetic Telegraph, 1845 (Box 25, Item 3)
  - McLouth, Lawrence A., Verses, 1910 (Box 25, Item 4)
  - Mathews, J.M., Recollections of Persons and Events, Chiefly in the City of New York: Being Selections From His Journal, 1865 (Box 25, Item 5)
  - Mathews, J.M., Recollections of Persons and Events, Chiefly in the City of New York: Being Selections From His Journal (copy 2), 1865 (Box 25, Item 6)
  - Stansbury, Howard, Expedition Maps of the Great Salt lake and Fort Leavenworth, 1850 (Box 25, Item 7)
  - Mathews, J.M., The Bible and Men of Learning, 1855 (Box 25, Item 8)
  - Mathews, J.M., The Bible and Civil Government, 1851 (Box 25, Item 9)
  - Mitchell, Allan C.G. and Zemansky, Mark W., Resonance Radiation and Excited Atoms, 1934 (Box 25, Item 10)
  - Prime, Samuel Irenæus, The Life of Samuel F.B. Morse, 1875 (Box 25, Item 11)
  - Prime, Samuel Irenæus, The Life of Samuel F.B. Morse (copy 2), 1875 (Box 25, Item 12)
  - Russell, Isaac Franklin, Outline Study of Law, 1894 (Box 25, Item 13)
  - McIlvaine, Charles P., "Collection of Lectures", Probably 1850s (Box 25, Item 14)
  - Monaghan, French Travellers in the United States 1765-1932 (A Bibliography), 1933 (Box 25, Item 15)
  - Sihler, Ernest G., C. Iulius Caesar, 1912 (Box 25, Item 16)
  - Paine, Martyn, A Review of Theoretical Geology, 1856 (Box 25, Item 17)
  - Russell, Isaac Franklin, Lectures on Law for Women, 1893 (Box 25, Item 18)
  - Nordheimer, Isaac, A Critical Grammar of the Hebrew Language, 1838 (Box 25, Item 19)
  - Stansbury, Howard, Exploration and Survey of the Valley of the Great Salt Lake of Utah, 1852 (Box 25, Item 20)
  - Muntz, Earl Edward, Race Contact, 1927 (Box 26, Item 1)
  - Stoddard, Franci Hovey, The Evolution of the English Novel, 1900 (Box 26, Item 2)
  - Still, Bayrd, Publications, 1935-1942 (Box 26, Item 3)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Second Geological Survey of Pennsylvania: 1877, Report of Progress in the Fayette & Westmoreland District of the Bituminous Coal-Fields of Western Pennsylvania, 1878 (Box 26, Item 4)
  - Stevenson, John. J., Formation of Coal Beds, 1911-1913 (Box 26, Item 5)
  - Stumpf, Stephen A., Choosing a Career in Business, 1984 (Box 26, Item 6)
  - Stoddard, Francis H., The Historical Study of English Grammar, 1886 (Box 26, Item 7)
  - Stoddard, Francis H., References for Students of Miracle Plays and Mysteries, 1887 (Box 26, Item 8)
  - Nason, Arthur H., Heralds and Heraldry in Jonson's Plays, 1907 (Box 26, Item 9)
  - Still, Bayrd, Milwaukee: The History of a City, 1948 (Box 26, Item 10)
  - Vail, Alfred, Early History of the Electro-Magnetic Telegraph, 1914 (Box 26, Item 11)
  - Archer, Gleason L., History of Radio to 1926, 1938 (Box 26, Item 12)
  - Still, Bayrd, German Counties in Pennsylvania, 1928 (Box 26, Item 13)
  - Still, Bayrd, State Constitutional Development in the United States 1829-1851, 1933 (Box 26, Item 14)
  - Stoianovich, Traian, Land Tenure and Related Sectors of the Balkan Economy, 1600-1800, 1953 (Box 26, Item 15)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Second Geological Survey of Pennsylvania: 1876, Report of Progress in the Fayette & Westmoreland District of the Bituminous Coal-Fields of Western Pennsylvania, 1877 (Box 26, Item 16)
  - Still, Bayrd, Milwaukee: The History of a City (copy 2), 1948 (Box 26, Item 17)
  - Still, Bayrd, Milwaukee: The History of a City, (Second Printing with new preface by the author), 1965 (Box 26, Item 18)
  - Morse, Samuel F.B., Amir Khan and Other Poems: The Remains of Lucretia Maria Davidson, 1829 (Box 26, Item 19)
  - Nason, Arthur Huntington, Talks on Theme Writing and Kindred Topics, 1909 (Box 26, Item 20)
  - Wehle, Harry B., Samuel F.B. Morse American Painter, 1932 (Box 26, Item 21)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Varia (Various Publications), 1877-1920 (Box 27, Item 1)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Geological Memoirs (Various Publications), 1871-1893 (Box 27, Item 2)
  - Smith, Homer W., Man and his Gods, 1952 (Box 27, Item 3)
  - Stevenson, John J., Geology of Northeastern New Mexico, 1881 (Box 27, Item 4)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Second Geological Survey of Pennsylvania: 1875, Report of Progress in the Greene and Washington District of the Bituminous Coal-Fields of Western Pennsylvania, 1876 (Box 27, Item 5)
  - Stevenson, J.J., Second Geological Survey of Pennsylvania: Report of Progress T2, The Geology of Bedford and Fulton Counties, 1882 (Box 27, Item 6)
  - Still, Bayrd, Mirror for Gotham, 1956 (Box 27, Item 7)
  - Stevenson, John J., The Carboniferous of the Appalachian Basin, 1903-1907 (Box 27, Item 8)
  - Stunkard, Horace W., Publications, 1934-1940 (Box 27, Item 10)
  - Stevenson, John J., Interrelations of the Fossil Fuels, 1916-1921 (Box 27, Item 9)
  - Stunkard, Horace W., Publications, 1915-1932 (Box 27, Item 11)